<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seminar on Ruoran Li</title>
    <link>/categories/seminar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seminar on Ruoran Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/seminar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutrition 2018: conference notes</title>
      <link>/2018/06/09/nutrition-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/09/nutrition-2018/</guid>
      <description>Lindsay Jaacks: US meat consumption is declining, but increasing globally. In China, meat production is increasing by 2 kg per person per year. (And diabetes is associated with small elevation by half serving of meat consumption in Nurses.) Global vegetable intake is low, and fruit intake is even lower.
 Carol Boushey: Food co-ocurrence pattern over time from new technologies that capture food intake. Interesting way to visualize multiple exposures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation &#43; data science: 4th Kolokotrones Symposium</title>
      <link>/2018/05/05/implementation-data-science-4th-kolokotrones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/05/implementation-data-science-4th-kolokotrones/</guid>
      <description>Several key concepts and learnings:
LAGO evaluation design Learn-as-you-go design presented by Daniel Nevo (paper not published yet): contrast with other types of trial designs.
The Kirkpatrick Model of learning evaluation:  Reaction - what participants thought and felt about the training (satisfaction; &amp;ldquo;smile sheets&amp;rdquo;) Learning - the resulting increase in knowledge and/or skills, and change in attitudes. This evaluation occurs during the training in the form of either a knowledge demonstration or test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Zero TB Initiative - talk by Mercedes Becerra</title>
      <link>/2018/05/03/the-zero-tb-initiative-talk-mercedes-becerra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/03/the-zero-tb-initiative-talk-mercedes-becerra/</guid>
      <description>Notes from a talk from the Global Health Delivery Partnership Grand Rounds series.
Title: Principles of Tuberculosis Elimination and the Zero TB Initiative
Presenter: Mercedes Becerra, ScD. Professor, Department of Global Health and Social Medicine, Harvard Medical School Associate Epidemiologist, Division of Global Health Equity, Brigham and Women’s Hospital Senior TB Specialist, Partners In Health
A substandard of TB control has been mainstream Based on current trend, it will take 200 years for the global incidence to be at the same level as TB incidence in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timely vaccines - talk by Kendall Hoyt</title>
      <link>/2018/05/03/timely-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/03/timely-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>Notes from a talk by Kendall Hoyt, ID epi seminar series.
During WWII, the world is very productive in developing and improving many vaccines.
Many barriers are organizational, not scientific.
What are some of the good organizational characteristics that facilitate speedy development?
 Top down governance Integrated across developmental phases and diciplines Situated in a community that facilitates information transfer  CEPI (Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations) - defines the problem as a speed problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>