<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflow on ruoran&#39;s epi notes</title>
    <link>/tags/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflow on ruoran&#39;s epi notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading notes: Design Thinking by Nigel Cross</title>
      <link>/2018/08/14/reading-notes-design-thinking-by-nigel-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/14/reading-notes-design-thinking-by-nigel-cross/</guid>
      <description>Nigel Cross: “Design Thinking.”
Informative book that helps me to reflect the design (research) process as an independent researcher.
Quotes “&amp;hellip; designing is not a search for the optimum solution to the given problem, but that it is an exploratory process. The creative designer interprets the design brief not as a specification for a solution, but as a starting point for a journey of exploration; the designer sets off to explore, to discover something new, rather than to reach somewhere already known, or to return with yet another example of the already familiar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting with R codes in tidyverse</title>
      <link>/2018/05/04/try-r-codes-and-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/04/try-r-codes-and-plots/</guid>
      <description>Set up I’m following the R for data science book to learn some better practices for organizing my analyses. My motivation for this is that I’ve only just realized that I have been using base R for most of my previous data cleaning works – maybe I should start learning to use packages that can simplify this process.
tidyverse may be the place to start (heard about it from Roger Peng and Hilary Parker’s podcast).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>