<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tb on Ruoran Li</title>
    <link>/tags/tb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tb on Ruoran Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering TB patients and providers: poster video at TBScience2018</title>
      <link>/2018/10/23/poster-video-at-tbscience2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/23/poster-video-at-tbscience2018/</guid>
      <description>We are presenting at TBScience2018 conference, part of the 49th Union World Conference on Lung Health.
Here&amp;rsquo;s our poster, poster #3384: I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded a screencast explaning the poster (7 minutes).
 Transcripts: Hello everyone! This is Ruoran Li. Here’s a five minutes overview of the poster we’re presenting at the TBScience 2018 conference.
This research is a collaboration between Harvard TH Chan school of Public Health, Harvard Medical School, and Socios En Salud in Peru.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Zero TB Initiative - talk by Mercedes Becerra</title>
      <link>/2018/05/03/the-zero-tb-initiative-talk-mercedes-becerra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/03/the-zero-tb-initiative-talk-mercedes-becerra/</guid>
      <description>Notes from a talk from the Global Health Delivery Partnership Grand Rounds series.
Title: Principles of Tuberculosis Elimination and the Zero TB Initiative
Presenter: Mercedes Becerra, ScD. Professor, Department of Global Health and Social Medicine, Harvard Medical School Associate Epidemiologist, Division of Global Health Equity, Brigham and Women’s Hospital Senior TB Specialist, Partners In Health
A substandard of TB control has been mainstream Based on current trend, it will take 200 years for the global incidence to be at the same level as TB incidence in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>