<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruoran Li</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ruoran Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a nutrition intervention for healthcare workers: poster for Nutrition 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/06/10/poster-for-nutrition-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/10/poster-for-nutrition-2018/</guid>
      <description>We are presenting this work at Nutrition 2018, in Boston, MA, on June 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutrition 2018: conference notes</title>
      <link>/2018/06/09/nutrition-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/09/nutrition-2018/</guid>
      <description>Lindsay Jaacks: US meat consumption is declining, but increasing globally. In China, meat production is increasing by 2 kg per person per year. (And diabetes is associated with small elevation by half serving of meat consumption in Nurses.) Global vegetable intake is low, and fruit intake is even lower.
 Carol Boushey: Food co-ocurrence pattern over time from new technologies that capture food intake. Interesting way to visualize multiple exposures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation &#43; data science: 4th Kolokotrones Symposium</title>
      <link>/2018/05/05/implementation-data-science-4th-kolokotrones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/05/implementation-data-science-4th-kolokotrones/</guid>
      <description>Several key concepts and learnings:
LAGO evaluation design Learn-as-you-go design presented by Daniel Nevo (paper not published yet): contrast with other types of trial designs.
The Kirkpatrick Model of learning evaluation:  Reaction - what participants thought and felt about the training (satisfaction; &amp;ldquo;smile sheets&amp;rdquo;) Learning - the resulting increase in knowledge and/or skills, and change in attitudes. This evaluation occurs during the training in the form of either a knowledge demonstration or test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting with R codes in tidyverse</title>
      <link>/2018/05/04/try-r-codes-and-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/04/try-r-codes-and-plots/</guid>
      <description>Set up I’m following the R for data science book to learn some better practices for organizing my analyses. My motivation for this is that I’ve only just realized that I have been using base R for most of my previous data cleaning works – maybe I should start learning to use packages that can simplify this process.
tidyverse may be the place to start (heard about it from Roger Peng and Hilary Parker’s podcast).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Zero TB Initiative - talk by Mercedes Becerra</title>
      <link>/2018/05/03/the-zero-tb-initiative-talk-mercedes-becerra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/03/the-zero-tb-initiative-talk-mercedes-becerra/</guid>
      <description>Notes from a talk from the Global Health Delivery Partnership Grand Rounds series.
Title: Principles of Tuberculosis Elimination and the Zero TB Initiative
Presenter: Mercedes Becerra, ScD. Professor, Department of Global Health and Social Medicine, Harvard Medical School Associate Epidemiologist, Division of Global Health Equity, Brigham and Women’s Hospital Senior TB Specialist, Partners In Health
A substandard of TB control has been mainstream Based on current trend, it will take 200 years for the global incidence to be at the same level as TB incidence in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timely vaccines - talk by Kendall Hoyt</title>
      <link>/2018/05/03/timely-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/03/timely-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>Notes from a talk by Kendall Hoyt, ID epi seminar series.
During WWII, the world is very productive in developing and improving many vaccines.
Many barriers are organizational, not scientific.
What are some of the good organizational characteristics that facilitate speedy development?
 Top down governance Integrated across developmental phases and diciplines Situated in a community that facilitates information transfer  CEPI (Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations) - defines the problem as a speed problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/2018/05/01/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/01/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>First post! I&amp;rsquo;ll use this space for sharing reading and research notes.
This site was created following the Blogdown book, using Yihui&amp;rsquo;s adaptation of the Lithium Hugo theme, adding tags and categories based on the Natrium theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a graduate student in epidemiology in the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health. I’m interested in using epidemiologic methods to identify targeted interventions for high risk populations. Before starting my doctoral degree, I worked in the London School of Hygiene &amp;amp; Tropical Medicine studying cancer survival disparities in the UK, France and Japan. For my doctoral thesis, I am working on using both infectious disease modeling and machine learning techniques to inform tuberculosis control strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Active projects TB contact investigation in Peru As part of my doctoral thesis, I&amp;rsquo;m developing tools that could inform tuberculosis contact investigation and preventive therapy for pulmonary TB patients and their contacts in Lima, Peru with Prof. Megan Murray.
 Some preliminary results were presented on the 16th Annual Jonathan Freeman Symposium on Infectious Disease Epidemiology on Apr 27, 2018.  Nutrition intervention in China Developing a worksite-based intervention in Pudong, Shanghai, collaborating with the Pudong Institute for Health Development and Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Harvard During my doctoral studies, my teaching activities include:
 EPI523: Investigating Outbreaks with Dr. Kayla Laserson. Fall 2015-18 EPI289: Causal Inference with Dr. Miguel Hernan. Spring 2017 EPI527: Design and Conduct of Clinical Trials in Preventive Medicine with Dr. Howard Sesso and Dr. I-Min Lee. Fall 2017-18 (online) ID201: Introduction to Epidemiology and Biostatistics with Dr. Kimberlee Gauvreau and Dr. Nina Paynter. Fall 2016 EPI236: Analytic Aspect of Clinical Epidemiolog with Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>