<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ruoran&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ruoran&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Doomsday Survival Code</title>
      <link>/2019/02/17/doomsday-survival-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/17/doomsday-survival-code/</guid>
      <description>I gave two lectures at the Public Health Symposium for Young Leaders in China, Feb 17, 2019, for 50+ high school students from several different regions in China.
Click here for slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering TB patients and providers: poster video at TBScience2018</title>
      <link>/2018/10/23/poster-video-at-tbscience2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/23/poster-video-at-tbscience2018/</guid>
      <description>We are presenting at TBScience2018 conference, part of the 49th Union World Conference on Lung Health.
Title: Empowering Patients &amp;amp; Providers, Prediction Tools to Improve TB Contact Investigation &amp;amp; Preventive Treatment.
I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded a screencast explaning the poster (7 minutes). Please see below for the poster and for full transcripts.
 Here&amp;rsquo;s our poster, poster #3384: High resolution pdf version
Transcripts Hello everyone! This is Ruoran Li. Here’s a seven minutes overview of the poster we’re presenting at the TBScience 2018 conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading notes: Design Thinking by Nigel Cross</title>
      <link>/2018/08/14/reading-notes-design-thinking-by-nigel-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/14/reading-notes-design-thinking-by-nigel-cross/</guid>
      <description>Nigel Cross: “Design Thinking.”
Informative book that helps me to reflect the design (research) process as an independent researcher.
Quotes “&amp;hellip; designing is not a search for the optimum solution to the given problem, but that it is an exploratory process. The creative designer interprets the design brief not as a specification for a solution, but as a starting point for a journey of exploration; the designer sets off to explore, to discover something new, rather than to reach somewhere already known, or to return with yet another example of the already familiar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dplyr saves lives</title>
      <link>/2018/07/19/dplyr-saves-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/19/dplyr-saves-lives/</guid>
      <description>Transitioning from Stata to R is painful. So for over half a year, I was using base R for data cleaning and manipulation (double PAINFUL!), before finally having time to learn the many uses of the dplyr package. Life is so much simpler. All thanks go to YouTube videos from Prof. Roger Peng: timesaver and lifesaver!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a nutrition intervention for healthcare workers: poster for Nutrition 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/06/10/poster-for-nutrition-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/10/poster-for-nutrition-2018/</guid>
      <description>We are presenting this work at Nutrition 2018, in Boston, MA, on June 11.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a PDF version of the poster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutrition 2018: conference notes</title>
      <link>/2018/06/09/nutrition-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/09/nutrition-2018/</guid>
      <description>Lindsay Jaacks: US meat consumption is declining, but increasing globally. In China, meat production is increasing by 2 kg per person per year. (And diabetes is associated with small elevation by half serving of meat consumption in Nurses.) Global vegetable intake is low, and fruit intake is even lower.
 Carol Boushey: Food co-ocurrence pattern over time from new technologies that capture food intake. Interesting way to visualize multiple exposures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation &#43; data science: 4th Kolokotrones Symposium</title>
      <link>/2018/05/05/implementation-data-science-4th-kolokotrones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/05/implementation-data-science-4th-kolokotrones/</guid>
      <description>Several key concepts and learnings:
LAGO evaluation design Learn-as-you-go design presented by Daniel Nevo (paper not published yet): contrast with other types of trial designs.
The Kirkpatrick Model of learning evaluation:  Reaction - what participants thought and felt about the training (satisfaction; &amp;ldquo;smile sheets&amp;rdquo;) Learning - the resulting increase in knowledge and/or skills, and change in attitudes. This evaluation occurs during the training in the form of either a knowledge demonstration or test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting with R codes in tidyverse</title>
      <link>/2018/05/04/try-r-codes-and-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/04/try-r-codes-and-plots/</guid>
      <description>Set up I’m following the R for data science book to learn some better practices for organizing my analyses. My motivation for this is that I’ve only just realized that I have been using base R for most of my previous data cleaning works – maybe I should start learning to use packages that can simplify this process.
tidyverse may be the place to start (heard about it from Roger Peng and Hilary Parker’s podcast).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Zero TB Initiative - talk by Mercedes Becerra</title>
      <link>/2018/05/03/the-zero-tb-initiative-talk-mercedes-becerra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/03/the-zero-tb-initiative-talk-mercedes-becerra/</guid>
      <description>Notes from a talk from the Global Health Delivery Partnership Grand Rounds series.
Title: Principles of Tuberculosis Elimination and the Zero TB Initiative
Presenter: Mercedes Becerra, ScD. Professor, Department of Global Health and Social Medicine, Harvard Medical School Associate Epidemiologist, Division of Global Health Equity, Brigham and Women’s Hospital Senior TB Specialist, Partners In Health
A substandard of TB control has been mainstream Based on current trend, it will take 200 years for the global incidence to be at the same level as TB incidence in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timely vaccines - talk by Kendall Hoyt</title>
      <link>/2018/05/03/timely-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/03/timely-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>Notes from a talk by Kendall Hoyt, ID epi seminar series.
During WWII, the world is very productive in developing and improving many vaccines.
Many barriers are organizational, not scientific.
What are some of the good organizational characteristics that facilitate speedy development?
 Top down governance Integrated across developmental phases and diciplines Situated in a community that facilitates information transfer  CEPI (Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations) - defines the problem as a speed problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/2018/05/01/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/01/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>First post! I&amp;rsquo;ll use this space for sharing reading and research notes.
This site was created following the Blogdown book, using Yihui&amp;rsquo;s adaptation of the Lithium Hugo theme, adding tags and categories based on the Natrium theme.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>