<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Research on ruoran&#39;s epi notes</title>
    <link>/categories/my-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Research on ruoran&#39;s epi notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/my-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research update</title>
      <link>/2020/02/28/research-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/28/research-update/</guid>
      <description>Active projects Developing a tuberculosis risk score I&amp;rsquo;m developing a tool to describe the distribution of TB risks in a population. Preliminary results were presented at the 50th Union World Conference on Lung Health in Hyderabad, India, on October 31, 2019.
COVID-19 inpatient resource needs As part of my doctoral thesis, I&amp;rsquo;m estimating the inpatient hospitalization needs for COVID-19.
Previous projects TB contact investigation in Peru I have developed tools that could inform tuberculosis contact investigation and preventive therapy for pulmonary TB patients and their contacts in Lima, Peru with Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering TB patients and providers: poster video at TBScience2018</title>
      <link>/2018/10/23/poster-video-at-tbscience2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/23/poster-video-at-tbscience2018/</guid>
      <description>We are presenting at TBScience2018 conference, part of the 49th Union World Conference on Lung Health.
Title: Empowering Patients &amp;amp; Providers, Prediction Tools to Improve TB Contact Investigation &amp;amp; Preventive Treatment.
I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded a screencast explaning the poster (7 minutes). Please see below for the poster and for full transcripts.
 Here&amp;rsquo;s our poster, poster #3384: High resolution pdf version
Transcripts Hello everyone! This is Ruoran Li. Here’s a seven minutes overview of the poster we’re presenting at the TBScience 2018 conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a nutrition intervention for healthcare workers: poster for Nutrition 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/06/10/poster-for-nutrition-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/10/poster-for-nutrition-2018/</guid>
      <description>We are presenting this work at Nutrition 2018, in Boston, MA, on June 11.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a PDF version of the poster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>